MD. SABBIR HOSSAIN

Front-end Developer

shr472978@gmail.com • +8801827062978

Portfolio: https://sabbirhossainc.github.io **GitHub:** https://github.com/sabbirhossainc **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/sabbirhossainbio

Summary

Software developer with 2 years of experience in **React.js**. Also learning **Next.js** for providing best performance. Developed various kind of platform Commitment of experience, passion and excellence with proven experiences.

Skills

HTML/CSS • Next.js • React.js • Figma • Tailwindcss • Rest API • Responsive design

Work Experience

Front end Developer Mar 2021 - Oct 2021

Expert Consortium Ltd. • Internship

Technologies: React • JavaScript • HTML/CSS

Junior React developer Dec 2022 - present

Xebec • Full-time

Technologies: React • JavaScript • Next.js • HTML/CSS

Projects

Blog application Project link

Technologies used: React.js • Redux • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Book Store Project link

Technologies used: React.js • API • Redux • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Shopping Cart Project link

Technologies used: React.js • Redux • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Employee management dashboard Project link

Technologies used: Next.js • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Flight Booking Project link

Technologies used: React.js • Redux • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Gallery pull Project link

Technologies used: React.js • Pixabay-API • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Education

Computer Science & Engineering

Jan 2017 - Dec 2020 • 4 yrs

Daffodil International University

Dhaka, Bangladesh Grade/GPA: 3.14

Certification

UX/UI Design - ICT Division Sep 2018

Full stack Web Development - Bohubrihi

Jan 2021

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Bengali (Native or bilingual proficiency)